GAUTAM SAPRE

gautamsapre@gmail.com | (617)396-1452 | 1704 Yellowthroat Dr. Little Elm, TX, 75068 | linkedin.com/in/gautam-sapre | github.com/gautamsapre

SUMMARY

Results-driven and passionate software developer experienced with Programming languages such as JAVA, Python (Django), C++, TypeScript, ReactJS, etc, and technologies such as AWS, Azure DevOps, Git, Unix, etc. Enthusiastic full-stack developer with experience in database management. Has previous technical internship experience in software from Communications and Power Industries (CPI), and Amazon (AWS).

EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineer Intern, Amazon -AWS

May 2023 - Aug 2023

- Developed and deployed a critical fullstack feature for CodeCatalyst's Source team, enhancing developer user experience by seamlessly integrating JAVA and ReactJS technologies.
- Spearheaded end-to-end project delivery, architecting scalable infrastructure that enabled seamless expansion of the product's capabilities, contributing to its long-term success.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design, code, and deploy essential APIs while demonstrating a deep understanding of software development principles.

Software Developement Engineer Intern, Amazon - AWS

May 2022 - Aug 2022

- Designed and implemented a new software feature for an extensive, distributed software application in a collaborative cross-team agile environment.
- Established a correct solution for a broadly defined problem, while ensuring performance, scalability, and usability.
- Exceeded predefined goals by 25% by achieving out-of-scope use cases through research and utilization of external resources.

Software Engineering Intern, Communication and Power Industries (CPI)

Nov 2020 - Mar 2022

- Assisted in a data migration project which included working with Azure DevOps and IBM RTC.
- Created Pipelines and Deployments in Azure for CPI's product line, e.g. Netmac which is an Antenna Control System.
- Explored Automated Testing solution for CPI's software products, worked with Test Complete, and reduce efforts of Test-Engineers by 20%.

PROJECTS

Intelligent Air Quality - Murata Manufacturing Co.

- Enhanced an occupancy estimator using data regarding air quality of a closed room. Led the front-end team to create a dynamic website to depict data produced by the machine learning models.
- Utilized the Django web framework in Python to display data and model estimations in an organized and eye-appealing fashion. Technologies Used: Django, Python, and ReactJS.

Carpool

- Created an android application that lets users match with people to carpool with who have similar commutes.
- Implemented a chat application that lets the users talk to people matched with. Utilized the Firebase database to store users' data. Technologies used: Java (Android Studio), Google Autocomplete API and Firebase

EDUCATION

Master's of Science, Computer Science - Data Science

Aug 2022 - Dec 2023

The University of Texas at Dallas

Bachelor's of Science, Computer Science

Aug 2018 - May 2022

The University of Texas at Dallas

SKILLS

Languages: JAVA, C++, Python, Javascript, TypeScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, Django, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, Markdown Technologies: Git, Linux, Unix, Firebase

Tools: AWS, Azure Devops, Github, Postman, Trello, Jira, Command Line, Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Cloud, Slack, Microsoft Teams

Soft: Entrepreneurship, Project Management, Adaptability, Conflict resolution, Communication Skills, Mentorship

Accomplishments

Organizations: Association of Computing Machinery (HackUTD): Industry Lead, Artificial Intelligence Society: Operations Coordinator

Awards: Academic Excellence Scholarship at the Honors Level Recipient

Courses: Machine Learning, Big Data, Database Design, Statistics in Data Science, C/C++ in a Unix Environment, Computer Networks, Computer Architecture, Data Structures and Algorithms, Linear Algebra.